<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Alana Higgins</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Alana Higgins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:49:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA DEVLEOP Belize Water Resources</title>
      <link>/projects/belizewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/belizewater/</guid>
      <description>Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena CA June 2019 to August 2019 For my second term with the NASA DEVELOP program, I was part of a Water Resources team. Over ten weeks, my team and I created a Google Earth Engine dashboard to analyze water quality parameters of the Belize Barrier Reef Reserve System in Central America.
The two parameters we studied were turbidity (water clarity) and chlorophyll-a (water color) concentrations, which are characterisitcs used as proxy data to determine water and reef health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA DEVELOP Alaska Ecological Forecasting</title>
      <link>/projects/alaskaecoii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 13:09:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/alaskaecoii/</guid>
      <description>Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena CA January 2019 to April 2019 During this ten week internship, I was the project lead in a team of educated young professionals with backgrounds in remote sensing, GIS, comuter science,data analysis, and of course, a passion for the environment.
Our project aimed to analyze wetland inundation in the state of Alaska using synthetic arperture radar (SAR) and optical imagery from Sentinel-1 and Landsat 8 satellite data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freelance Geospatial Consulting for University Professor</title>
      <link>/projects/soilmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/soilmaps/</guid>
      <description>California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo May 2019 As an active member in my university&amp;rsquo;s GIS community, I aided Dr. Christopher Appel of the Natural Resources and Environmental Science Department in creating soil maps for his ongoing research project of soils in the Me Wuk Tribe Ranch. I created three maps visualizing soil groupings, soil pH values, and potential soil vigor.
I was initially given paper maps with polygons drawn by hand deliniating soil type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lopez Lake Recreation Area Field Work and GIS Consulting</title>
      <link>/projects/lopezlake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/lopezlake/</guid>
      <description>California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo January 2018 to May 2018 The Lopez Lake Recreation Area is a popular gathering place for outdoor enthusiasts on the Central Coast of California. For this project, a team of nine Cal Poly students, including myself, visited the site to conduct field work and collect GPS coordinates of all campsites and utility features in the park. We utilized the Trible Geo 7x GPS unit and Pathfinder software to collect and process the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Data Driven Pages for City Zoning</title>
      <link>/projects/datadrivenpages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/datadrivenpages/</guid>
      <description>California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo February 2018 Urbanized areas are often difficult to represent spatially as cities have high population densities and landuse can change frequently. Data Driven Pages is a useful tool in the ArcMap toolbox that allows users to break up the area of their city page by page. Each page represents one square unit of an entire city grid. By including an inset map, users can gauge where they are within the city for better context.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>