<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alana Higgins</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alana Higgins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/post/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/about/</guid>
      <description>I was born and raised on the island of Oahu, Hawaii. After graduating from high school in 2015, I moved to the Central Coast of California to attend California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo. I majored in Environmental Earth and Soil Science with an emphasis in geospatial technologies. Some of my other academic interests included geography, graphic design, and urban planning.
During my time at Cal Poly, I became part of the San Luis Obispo community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA DEVELOP Belize Water Resources</title>
      <link>/post/belizewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/belizewater/</guid>
      <description>Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena CA
June 2019 to August 2019
During my second term with the NASA DEVELOP program, I was part of a Water Resources project. Over ten weeks, my team and I created a Google Earth Engine dashboard to analyze water quality parameters of the Belize Barrier Reef Reserve System in Central America. Our main objective was to support the environmental decision making efforts of our international partners, the Wildlife Conservation Society and the Coastal Zone Management Authority and Institute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA DEVELOP Alaska Ecological Forecasting II</title>
      <link>/post/alaskaeco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 13:09:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/alaskaeco/</guid>
      <description>Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena CA
January 2019 to April 2019
During this ten-week internship, I was the project lead in a team of educated young professionals with backgrounds in remote sensing, GIS, computer science, earth science, and data analysis.
Our project identified wetland inundation in the state of Alaska using synthetic aperture radar (SAR) and optical imagery from Sentinel-1 MSI and Landsat 8 OLI satellite data. We built on the previous team&amp;rsquo;s SAR Wetland Extent Exploration Tool (SWEET), a Python-based algorithm that detected inundation type based on seasonality and vegetation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freelance Geospatial Consulting for University Professor</title>
      <link>/post/soilmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 13:09:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/soilmaps/</guid>
      <description>California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo
May 2019
As an active member in my university&amp;rsquo;s GIS community, I aided Dr. Christopher Appel of the Natural Resources and Environmental Science Department in creating soil maps for his ongoing research project of soils in the Me Wuk Tribe Ranch. I created three maps visualizing soil groupings, soil pH values, and potential soil vigor.
I was initially given paper maps with polygons drawn by hand delineating soil type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phase I Environmental Site Assessment</title>
      <link>/post/phasei/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 13:09:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/phasei/</guid>
      <description>California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo
April 2019
A Phase I Environmental Site Assessment is a common evaluation done to identify environmental hazards or liabilities on a property. They are often required for land appraisals, real estate transactions, or building development. Common hazards include leaking gas or septic tanks, contaminated wells, and improperly stored chemicals, as these substances may seep into groundwater basins or public waterways.
This report was the final project for my Environmental Applications of Soils Science (SSC 562), a graduate level course taken remotely through North Carolina State University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Construction Environmental Assessment</title>
      <link>/post/construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 13:09:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/construction/</guid>
      <description>California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo
April 2019
Construction is a primary source of soil erosion and hydrologic degradation. This report assesses the post-construction environment of a newly built apartment complex by comparing the pre-construction hydrology to post-construction hydrology. Specifically, runoff and peak flow values are calculated to draw conclusions about the impact of anthropogenic disturbance. This report was written as a component of my Soil Erosion and Water Conservation (ERSC 303) course at Cal Poly San Luis Obispo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stormwater Runoff Assessment of Cerro Vista Apartment Complex</title>
      <link>/post/stormwater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 13:09:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stormwater/</guid>
      <description>California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo
December 2018
A stormwater management plan is a necessary precaution many construction companies must take to ensure that the new development considers the runoff of natural storms or weather disturbances. In this fictional report done as part of my Soil Erosion and Water Conservation course (ERSC 303) at Cal Poly, I analyzed the infiltration capacity of a stormwater runoff site near university dorms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lopez Lake Recreation Area GIS Consulting</title>
      <link>/post/lopezlake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 13:09:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lopezlake/</guid>
      <description>California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo
January 2018 to May 2018
The Lopez Lake Recreation Area is a popular gathering place for outdoor enthusiasts on the Central Coast of California. For this project, a team of nine Cal Poly students, including myself, visited the site to conduct field work and collect GPS coordinates of all campsites and utility features in the park. We utilized the Trimble Geo 7x GPS unit and Pathfinder software to collect and process the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Data Driven Pages for City Zoning</title>
      <link>/post/datadrivenpages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 13:09:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/datadrivenpages/</guid>
      <description>California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo
February 2018
Urbanized areas are often difficult to represent spatially as cities have high population densities and land use can change frequently. Data Driven Pages is a useful tool in the ArcMap toolbox that allows users to break up the area of their city page by page. Each page represents one square unit of an entire city grid. By including an inset map, users can gauge where they are within the city for better context.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>